<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Krakow Tour Guide</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="wawel">A gorgeous assortment of predominantly Romanesque, Renaissance and Gothic architecture dating from around the 14th century onwards, Wawel is the crown jewel of Kraków\'s architectural treasures and required visiting for Poles and foreigners alike.</string>
    <string name="kosciuszko">Greeting visitors above the northern entrance to Wawel Castle is the slightly larger-than-life bronze likeness of Tadeusz Kościuszko on horseback, graciously doffing his cap to the crowds. One of the city\'s most popular pomniks (monuments), the hero of Polish and American freedom was created by Polish sculptor Leonard Marconi</string>
    <string name="arm_museum"><![CDATA[Containing Poland’s very own equivalent of the Crown Jewels among its many wonders, Wawel\'s Crown Treasury & Armoury provides a delightful excursion into the world of the sumptuous, extravagant and brutally violent. To the left, the Crown Treasury features several glass cases of golden and bejewelled goblets, platters, coins and other marvels, of which Szczerbiec - the country’s original coronation sword - is the ultimate highlight. To the right the Armoury contains a wealth of weaponry including some exceedingly swanky crossbows and a frightening array of spiky pikes, while the cellar holds a collection of cannons and replicas of the banners captured at the Battle of Grunwald.]]></string>
    <string name="dragon">Standing on the Wisła riverbank in the shade of Wawel Castle is a rather ugly likeness of the Wawel Dragon (Smok Wawelski), who - according to local legend - once reposed in the large cave behind him when not out and about in town scarfing up virgins and sheep. Finally vanquished when he was tricked into eating a bag of sulphur, this monument in his honour was unveiled in 1972 to a design by the local artist Bronisław Chromy</string>
    <string name="mariacki">After Tartar raids in the 13th century left the original church in a heap of ruins, St. Mary’s was rebuilt in Gothic style on the existing foundations and consecrated in 1320. In the early 15th century the towers took the iconic form they have today, when the northern tower was raised to 80m high and made into a watchtower for the city. It is from here that the hejnał mariacki - the city\'s famous bugle call - is played every hour on the hour. One of the city\'s most enduring traditions, the tune ironically breaks off mid-melody in honour of the mythical trumpeter who was shot in the neck while belatedly warning the city of Mongol invaders; don\'t miss it.</string>
    <string name="market">Kraków’s main market square (Rynek) serves as the city’s gravitational centre, and is the natural start and finish point for any tour of the city. Originally designed in 1257 - the year Kraków was awarded its charter – the grid-like layout of the Old Town and its central square has changed little in the years that have followed. Measuring 200 metres square, the Rynek ranks as one of the largest medieval squares in Europe, and is surrounded by elegant townhouses, all with their own unique names, histories and curiosities.</string>
    <string name="mound">History produces few men like Tadeusz Kościuszko (1746-1817). Having fought with distinction in the American War of Independence before inspiring a valiant Insurrection against foreign rule in Poland, this relentless freedom-fighter was described by Thomas Jefferson as ‘the purest son of liberty that I have ever known.’ Upon his passing Polish authorities demanded his body be sent from Switzerland to be interred in the Wawel Royal Crypts. Such was the love for Kościuszko that the people proposed to honour him with a monument in the tradition of the prehistoric mounds of King Krak and Wanda – and to make it the grandest in Kraków.</string>
    <string name="francis">If you only visit one church in Kraków, make it this one. Built in the 13th century, St. Francis\' Basilica was the first brick building in Kraków, but its legacy was forged at turn of the century when Wyspiański filled the interior with colourful Art Nouveau murals that deftly balance the organic and geometric with unique floral patterns. Wyspiański also designed the church\'s magnificent stained glass windows, including the imposing, almost violently energetic ‘God in the Act of Creation’ window over its rear entrance. Argued by some to be the greatest modern stained glass window in the world, it is certainly a must-see for all visitors.</string>
    <string name="korale">This traditional Polish restaurant may be discreet from the street, but the interior is one of the most vibrant and welcoming in the Old Town. The simple, but charming folk decor favours colour over clutter: cheerful chandeliers wrapped in wicker wreaths wound with bright ribbons and beads give the dining rooms a warm glow, while photos of dancing highlanders and peasant maidens frolicking in folk costumes line the walls. Even more colour comes from the kitchen, which serves all the Polish standards, but with some creative innovations and a flair for presentation that we were hardly expecting.</string>
    <string name="bar13">Formerly known as Bar 13, Likus has revamped their excellent wine bar more in the mould of their other culinary successes, and now serves modern Polish cuisine with Italian influences. Drawing from the exclusive vintages (served by the glass or bottle) and local delicacies of the adjacent delicatessen and wine shop, the dining room features a contemporary open kitchen and minimalist menu that uses fresh seasonal ingredients to create rich, signature dishes. Located in Pasaż 13, dining in the cellar of a shopping mall has never been this classy.</string>
    <string name="pierogi">Great pierogi are served in this bizarre little Polish place, where two oversized paintings of medieval knights greet you upon entering. Take the raised table and feast on both the pierogi and the beetroot soup, an unexpected delight served with great ravioli.</string>
    <string name="baroque">An attractive, modern lounge with a great hidden garden in the back and dancing downstairs, Baroque is known foremost as a cocktail bar with a drinks menu that is second to none, including an impressive 100 or so vodkas. Baroque has upped their game recently with regular live bands Thu-Sat and an expanded menu of modern twists on Italian and Polish cuisine, including a decent spread of salad, pasta, pizza and grilled salmon, as well as daily promotions.</string>
    <string name="wawel_hotel">Already one of the top mid-range offers in the city centre, Wawel was the beneficiary of a recent renovation, making it even more of a steal. Set inside a historic townhouse, some of the 19th century secessionist touches have survived, including the glass roof of the entrance and iron balustrade of the stairwell. A magnificent muralled courtyard will have you wishing it was summer all year round, while the fabulous mosaicked wellness centre will have you not caring to step outside at all.</string>
    <string name="art_blue">A five-star hotel and spa on a quiet corner of the Wisła riverbank, the Niebieski is designed to be environmentally sustainable and energy efficient, with a harmonious holistic interior arrangement and philosophy of well-being that extends from the excellent Vanilla SPA throughout the entire hotel.</string>
    <string name="komorowski">This honeymoon haven has all the hallmarks to make it the perfect romantic getaway including king-size beds, heated floors, 40-inch LCD televisions and two-person Jacuzzis with jet massage - some rooms even include tubs with water illumination and built-in stereos, as an in-room waterfall tinkles nearby. (We couldn\'t find the button that makes rose petals fall from the ceiling, but we\'re sure it\'s there somewhere.) Tastefully designed in Art Deco style, these immaculate rooms represent the highest standards in Kraków, buoyed by the personal service of owners Jerry and Bart themselves.</string>
    <string name="pollera">A beautiful stained-glass window by Stanisław Wyspiański over the staircase is the first thing to catch the eye. The bathrooms and furnishings are old but functional and the rooms are otherwise fully equipped. You might not get all new amenities, but you do get an over 180-year-old tradition.</string>
    <string name="chopin">Enjoy the music of Poland\'s greatest composer, Fryderyk Chopin, as performed by pianists Witold Wilczek, Weronika Krówka, Maria Moliszewska, Kazuko Tsuji and others. Concerts begin each day at 19:00 at Chopin Gallery, ul. Sławkowska 14. Price includes a glass of wine.</string>
    <string name="festival">Started by Teatr KTO in 1988 (believe it or not, that makes it one of the oldest events of this type in Central Europe), ULICA Street Theatre Festival has become one of Kraków\'s most colourful and vibrant yearly traditions. Drawing international theatre troupes with acts specially designed to be performed in public spaces, Kraków\'s streets and squares will be filled with spectacular, amusing and unusual happenings during the course of the festival.</string>
    <string name="exhibit">Right on the market square of Poland’s UNESCO-enshrined cultural capital comes this tourist-baiting and church-agitating exhibit of erotic art inspired by the trashy but titillating novel 50 Shades of Grey, and also, according to the organisers, by the history of the Kromerowska townhouse at Rynek Główny 23 in which it is housed</string>
    <string name="jazz">Kraków spoils its jazz fans in June and July when fantastic concerts take place every day for over a month during the Summer Jazz Festival. First organised in 1996 to celebrate the 40th anniversary of the important artistic and literary venue Piwnica Pod Baranami, the festival has gradually grown into the biggest jazz festival in Poland, expanding to include other music clubs and even hosting larger concerts by international stars. This year daily concerts will be held at 21:00 in Piwnica Pod Baranami (Rynek Główny 27, I-5) and at 21:30 in Harris Piano Jazz Bar (Rynek Główny 28, I-5)</string>
    <string name="bakery">If you\'re taking notes on how to start a successful business, this gourmet patisserie really has its act together. Created by the titular tag-team of Nad (French) and Greg (Belgian), it starts with their dedication to the craft - meticulously making each pastry, croissant, eclair, cake, macaron (and so much more!) by hand, from fresh seasonal fruits and the finest natural ingredients to result in absolutely delicious artisanal sweets. You can really taste the difference; in fact you can see it too.</string>
    <string name="cafe">A top-notch, modern cafe in an area where the pickings are a bit thin, Mo-ja offers a huge selection of breakfast and lunch options with a conscious bent towards vegan and gluten-free diets. There\'s something for all tastes and appetites, from the simple granola, omelettes, salads and toasted sandwiches, to more original creations like the popular \'breakfast burger\' (basically a glorified egg sandwich loaded with goodness), and the sweet potato wrap with avocado, hummus, eggs, orange, sprouts and greens.</string>
    <string name="copernicus">You’ve chosen well. Few hotels in Central Europe can match the standard set by Copernicus, and it’s a firm favourite of visiting dignitaries, with former guests including George W. Bush. Tastefully uncluttered the hotel is decorated with heavy woodwork, marble, rich fabrics and wall frescoes – some dating from the 14th century. Enjoy rooftop terrace views of Wawel, gourmet food or the spa, fitness centre and swimming pool - all three housed in the medieval cellars.</string>
    <string name="orchestra">This rather prolific ensemble of graduates from the Kraków Academy of Music perform outstanding, and outstandingly popular, classical music recitals around the Old Town. On even days of the month catch them at St. Adalbert\'s Church on the market square, beginning at 18:00.</string>
    <string name="wawel1">Wawel</string>
    <string name="wawel2">Royal Castle</string>
    <string name="kosciuszko1">Kosciuszko</string>
    <string name="kosciuszko2">Monument</string>
    <string name="armoury1"><![CDATA[Crown Treasury & Armoury]]></string>
    <string name="armoury2">Museum</string>
    <string name="dragon1">The Wawel Dragon</string>
    <string name="dragon2">Statue</string>
    <string name="stmary">St. Mary’s</string>
    <string name="basilica">Basilica</string>
    <string name="stfrancis">St. Francis’</string>
    <string name="kosciuszko01">Kosciuszko</string>
    <string name="kosciuszko02">Mound</string>
    <string name="mainmarket">Main Market</string>
    <string name="square">Square</string>
    <string name="chopin_concerts">Chopin Concerts</string>
    <string name="chopin_choncerts_date">19:00 Everyday\nJun 1 2017 - Dec 31 2017</string>
    <string name="festival1">Street Theatre Festival</string>
    <string name="festival2">Everyday\nJul 5 2017 - Jul 9 2017</string>
    <string name="erotic1">Erotic Art Exhibit</string>
    <string name="erotic2">Everyday\nFeb 14 2017 - Dec 31 2017</string>
    <string name="jazz1">Summer Jazz Festival</string>
    <string name="jazz2">Everyday\nJun 18 2017 - Jul 29 2017</string>
    <string name="orchestra1">Royal Chamber Orchestra</string>
    <string name="orchestra2">18:00 Everyday\nJun 1 2017 - Dec 31 2017</string>
    <string name="hotel_wawel">Wawel</string>
    <string name="hotel">Hotel</string>
    <string name="niebieski1">Niebieski Art</string>
    <string name="niebieski2"><![CDATA[Hotel & Spa]]></string>
    <string name="komor1">Komorowski</string>
    <string name="komor2">Luxury Guest Rooms</string>
    <string name="pollera1">Pollera</string>
    <string name="copernicus1">Copernicus</string>
    <string name="korale1">Czerwone Korale</string>
    <string name="restaurant">Restaurant</string>
    <string name="l13conc">L Concept 13</string>
    <string name="l13conc2"><![CDATA[Bar & Restaurant]]></string>
    <string name="bohema1">Bohema</string>
    <string name="baroq1">Baroque</string>
    <string name="baroq2"><![CDATA[Music & Coctails]]></string>
    <string name="nad_greg1"><![CDATA[Nad & Greg]]></string>
    <string name="nad_greg2">French Bakery</string>
    <string name="moja1">Mo-ja</string>
    <string name="moja2">Cafe</string>
    <string name="tab0_string">See</string>
    <string name="tab1_string">Eat</string>
    <string name="tab2_string">Sleep</string>
    <string name="tab3_string">Events</string>
</resources>